<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/AccountApi"
  xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright>Copyright © 2020 Alexander Akulich</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA.
</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.AccountApi">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>An AccountApi object provides access to account-specific API available
      without an active Connection.</p>

      <p>AccountApi instances are uniquely identified by object path. The
      object path of an AccountApi MUST take the form
        <code>/org/freedesktop/Telepathy/AccountApi/<em>cm</em>/<em>proto</em>/<em>acct</em></code>, where:</p>

      <ul>
        <li><em>cm</em> is the same <tp:type>Connection_Manager_Name</tp:type>
          that appears in the connection manager's well-known bus name and
          object path</li>
        <li><em>proto</em> is the <tp:type>Protocol</tp:type> name as seen in
          <tp:dbus-ref
          namespace="org.freedesktop.Telepathy">ConnectionManager.ListProtocols</tp:dbus-ref>,
          but with "-" replaced with "_"
          (i.e. the same as in the object-path of a <tp:dbus-ref
          namespace="org.freedesktop.Telepathy">Connection</tp:dbus-ref>)</li>
        <li><em>acct</em> is an arbitrary string of ASCII letters, digits
          and underscores, starting with a letter or underscore, which
          uniquely identifies this account</li>
        <li>Clients SHOULD parse the object path to discover the
          connection manager and protocol</li>
        <li>Clients MUST NOT attempt to parse <em>acct</em></li>
        <li>Clients MUST NOT assume that <em>acct</em> matches
          the connection-specific part of a Connection's object-path and
          bus name</li>
        <li>The account manager SHOULD choose <em>acct</em> such that if
          an account is deleted, its object path will be re-used if and only
          if the new account is in some sense "the same"
          (incorporating the 'account' parameter in some way is
          recommended)</li>
      </ul>
    </tp:docstring>
    <tp:added version="0.UNRELEASED">(draft 1)</tp:added>

    <property name="Interfaces" tp:name-for-bindings="Interfaces"
      access="read" type="as" tp:type="DBus_Interface[]">
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>The set of optional interfaces supported by this AccountApi
          instance.</p>
      </tp:docstring>
    </property>

  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
