<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Channel_Type_File_Transfer_Local_File"
  xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright>Copyright (C) 2008 Collabora Ltd.</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

    <p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

    <p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA
02110-1301, USA.</p>
  </tp:license>

  <interface
    name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Channel.Type.FileTransfer.LocalFile.DRAFT"
    tp:causes-havoc="experimental">

    <tp:requires
      interface="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Channel.Type.FileTransfer.DRAFT"/>

    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>This interface should be used when using the socket interface of
      <tp:dbus-ref namespace="org.freedesktop.Telepathy">Channel.Type.FileTransfer.DRAFT</tp:dbus-ref>
      cannot be used. Instead of using sockets to transfer the file from
      the client to the connection manager (and vice versa), the name of
      the file on the local filesystem is passed.</p>
    </tp:docstring>

    <property name="Filename" tp:name-for-bindings="Filename" type="s"
      access="read">
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>The full path to the file being transferred on the sender's side.
        This cannot change once the channel has been created.</p>

        <p>This property is mandatory when requesting the channel with the
        <tp:dbus-ref namespace="org.freedesktop.Telepathy">Connection.Interface.Requests.CreateChannel</tp:dbus-ref>
        method. This property cannot be empty and must be set to a sensible value.</p>
      </tp:docstring>
    </property>

  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
