<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Client"
  xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright>Copyright (C) 2008 Collabora Ltd.</tp:copyright>
  <tp:copyright>Copyright (C) 2008 Nokia Corporation</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA.
</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Client.DRAFT"
    tp:causes-havoc="experimental">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Telepathy clients use connection managers, the channel dispatcher
        and optionally the account manager to provide useful
        functionality.</p>

      <p>User interface processes are the obvious example of Telepathy
        clients, but they can provide other functionality, such as
        address-book synchronization.</p>

      <p>The Client D-Bus interface mainly represents a process to which the
        channel dispatcher can dispatch channels.</p>

      <!-- FIXME: or does it represent any of observer, approver or
      channel handler? We just don't know -->
    </tp:docstring>

    <property name="Interfaces" type="as" access="read"
      tp:type="DBus_Interface[]">
      <tp:docstring>
        A list of the extra interfaces provided by this client.
      </tp:docstring>
    </property>

    <property name="HandledChannelClasses" access="read" type="a(su)">
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      </tp:docstring>

      <!-- FIXME: invent and document a tp:type when it's clearer what we
      need. This is conjectured to be an array of (channel type, handle type)
      for now, hence a(su) -->
    </property>

  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
