<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Connection_Manager_Interface_Account_Api"
  xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">

  <tp:copyright>Copyright © 2020 Alexander Akulich</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
      modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
      License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
      version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

    <p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
      but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
      MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
      Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

    <p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
      License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
      Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA
      02110-1301, USA.</p>
  </tp:license>

  <interface name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.ConnectionManager.Interface.AccountApi.DRAFT"
    tp:causes-havoc="experimental">
    <tp:added version="0.UNRELEASED">(draft 1)</tp:added>
    <tp:requires interface="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.ConnectionManager"/>

    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>An interface for connection managers that expose account API
        available without an active Connection.</p>
    </tp:docstring>

    <signal name="NewApiInstance" tp:name-for-bindings="New_Api_Instance">
      <arg name="Bus_Name" type="s" tp:type="DBus_Bus_Name">
        <tp:docstring>
          The D-Bus service where the AccountApi object can be found
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg name="Object_Path" type="o">
        <tp:docstring>
          The object path of the AccountApi object on this service
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg name="Protocol" type="s" tp:type="Protocol">
        <tp:docstring>
          The identifier for the protocol this connection uses
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Emitted when a new <tp:dbus-ref
        namespace="org.freedesktop.Telepathy">AccountApi</tp:dbus-ref> object
        is created.
      </tp:docstring>
    </signal>

    <method name="RequestApi" tp:name-for-bindings="Request_Api">
      <arg direction="in" name="Protocol" type="s" tp:type="Protocol">
        <tp:docstring>
          The protocol identifier
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="in" name="Parameters" type="a{sv}"
        tp:type="String_Variant_Map">
        <tp:docstring>
          A dictionary mapping parameter names to values of the appropriate
          type, as indicated by
          <tp:dbus-ref namespace="ofdT.ConnectionManager">GetParameters</tp:dbus-ref>
          and the well-known list of names and value types documented on the
          <tp:type>Connection_Parameter_Name</tp:type> type.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="out" type="s" tp:type="DBus_Bus_Name" name="Bus_Name">
        <tp:docstring>
          A D-Bus service name where the new AccountApi object can be found
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="out" type="o" name="Object_Path">
        <tp:docstring>
          The D-Bus object path to the AccountApi on this service
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Request a
          <tp:dbus-ref namespace="org.freedesktop.Telepathy">AccountApi</tp:dbus-ref>
          object representing a given account on a given
          protocol with the given parameters. The method returns the bus name
          and the object path where the new AccountApi object can be found.</p>

        <p>The parameters which must and may be provided in the parameters
        dictionary can be discovered with the
        <tp:dbus-ref namespace="ofdT.ConnectionManager">GetParameters</tp:dbus-ref>
        method. These
        parameters, their types, and their default values may be cached
        in files so that all available connection managers do not need to be
        started to discover which protocols are available.</p>

        <p>Every successful RequestApi call will cause the emission of a
        <tp:member-ref>NewApiInstance</tp:member-ref> signal for the same newly
        created object. The
        requester can use the returned object path and service name
        independently of the emission of that signal. In that case this signal
        emission is most useful for, e.g. other processes that are monitoring
        the creation of new connections.</p>
      </tp:docstring>
      <tp:possible-errors>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.NotImplemented">
          <tp:docstring>
            The requested protocol is not supported by this manager
          </tp:docstring>
        </tp:error>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.NotAvailable">
          <tp:docstring>
            The requested API object already appears to exist
          </tp:docstring>
        </tp:error>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.InvalidArgument">
          <tp:docstring>
            Unrecognised connection parameters
          </tp:docstring>
        </tp:error>
      </tp:possible-errors>
    </method>

  </interface>
</node>
