<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Sidecar"
  xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0"
  >
  <tp:copyright>Copyright © 2009 Collabora Limited</tp:copyright>
  <tp:copyright>Copyright © 2009 Nokia Corporation</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301,
USA.</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Sidecar.DRAFT"
    tp:causes-havoc="just a sketch">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Base interface for once-per-<tp:dbus-ref
        namespace="org.freedesktop.Telepathy">Connection</tp:dbus-ref> objects,
        providing functionality which does not belong on a connection
        interface. This interface does not have any functionality of its own,
        beyond a list of interfaces implemented by the sidecar.</p>

      <p>Sidecar objects are destroyed when their connection moves to state
        Disconnected.</p>

      <p>FIXME:</p>

      <ul>
        <li>Does this need a back-reference to its Connection?</li>
      </ul>
    </tp:docstring>

    <property name="Interfaces" tp:name-for-bindings="Interfaces"
      type="as" tp:type="DBus_Interface[]" access="read">
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Interfaces implemented by this sidecar, beside the Sidecar interface
          itself. These cannot change after creation of the object.</p>
      </tp:docstring>
    </property>
  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
